telekom.jobs 2019-06-29

# Privacy Statement │ Job Search

**1\. General**

Deutsche Telekom AG takes safeguarding your personal data extremely seriously. It is important to us that you know what personal data we collect when you visit our website, how these data are used and what your options are in this regard. In order to protect your data from unauthorised access and misuse, we've implemented a comprehensive range of technical and procedural security measures in conformity with the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

 **2\. Collection, processing and use of personal data**

_Access data/ server log files:_

When you visit our website, the IP address of the device you use (e.g. computer) is temporarily stored in so-called log files. The lawful basis for using the logged data is Article 6(1f) of the GDPR and these data are used exclusively for the purposes of data security, in particular, to protect against attempts to hack our web servers, and for statistical analyses. These data are not made available to third parties and are deleted after four weeks at the latest.

 _Website analysis using Webtrekk/ use of Cookies:_

Within the scope of the statutory provisions, we, or one of our authorised contractors, create user profiles using a pseudonym. It is not possible to directly associate these user profiles with you personally. The profile data is not linked to any of your personal data. The lawful basis for processing the data is, according to Article 6(1f) of the GDPR, our legitimate interest in the statistical analysis of the behaviour of visitors to our website and in using the data to design and optimise our website according to requirements. In the following, we let you know about the procedures used on our website and how you can object at any time.

We use services provided by the company [Webtrekk GmbH](https://www.webtrekk.com/en/home/) to collect data on the usage of the website and to optimise our service accordingly. Webtrekk GmbH is certified by the TÜV for data security in the field of web controlling software. When you visit our website, information is collected and analysed that your browser transmits. These data are collected by means of a web bug that is embedded in each page. A signature, composed of various pieces of information automatically transmitted by your computer, is used for recognition purposes. The following cookies are set by Webtrekk in addition:

\- Session cookie (for session recognition, lifespan: one session)  
\- Persistent cookie (to identify new/regular customers: six months)  
\- Opt-out cookie (to prevent tracking: 60 months)

Webtrekk GmbH only stores the IP address in truncated (anonymised) form and only uses it for session recognition, for geo localisation (down to city level) and to defend against hacking attempts. The IP address is immediately deleted afterwards, so that the collected data are then anonymous. You can object to Webtrekk processing your data at any time by clicking the following link: [I do not want to be tracked by Webtrekk!](https://telekom.jobs/#) _Job alert:_

If you sign up to be notified about job offers on our website, you will be asked to provide your email address. This will be stored and processed on the basis of Article 6(1f) of the GDPR so that we're able to periodically send you job offers that may be of interest to you by email. Your email address will be stored and processed by us until you withdraw your consent for us to do so. You can unsubscribe from receiving job offer notifications at any time via the link that is contained in every email we send you, and withdraw your consent to our storing and processing your email address for this purpose.

 **3\. Integration of third-party services and content:**

Our website includes content provided by third-party service providers. When you open a page on our site, your IP address may be transmitted to one or more third-party service providers.

Using this content enables us to provide greater detail about the job vacancies and the departments making the offers in order to provide a better service and make it more interesting for you as a user. The legal basis for the use of such content by third-party service providers is thus Article 6(1f) of the GDPR.

You can find a list of the third-party service providers and the used content as well as links to their data privacy statements below. We have no control over what data is collected or the data processing procedures, nor are we aware of the full scope of data collected, the purpose of processing or retention periods. We have no information about the respective third-party service provider's deletion policy for the collected data either.

\- Map material from the "Google Maps" service published by third-party service provider Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre, Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>

\- Feed from third-party service provider Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA; <https://twitter.com/privacy>

**4\. Embedding of social media plugins**

Some of the pages on our site include plugins for social networks. We currently use the following plugins: Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Google+, YouTube, kununu, whatchado, Xing and LinkedIn.

To ensure that full control over your data remains in your hands, we use the so-called two-click solution. This means that when you visit our website, no personal data is passed on to the providers of the plugins at first. You can identify the provider of the plugin by the markings on the icon, by the initial letters or the logo. We provide you with the option of using the button to communicate directly with the provider of the plugin. Only when you activate it by clicking on the marked area does the plugin provider receive information about you having visited the corresponding page of our website. Additional data, in particular, your IP address, are also transmitted. Thus by activating the plugin, some of your personal data is transmitted by you to the plugin provider where it is then stored.

We use plugins to enable you to visit our company profiles on the various social networks, share job offers and thereby interact with other users. Doing so allows us to offer a better service and make it more interesting for you as a user. The legal basis for the use of plugins is thus Article 6(1f) of the GDPR.

We have no control over what data is collected or the data processing procedures, nor are we aware of the full scope of data collected, the purpose of processing or retention periods. We have no information about the respective network's deletion policy for the collected data either. You can find further information on this in the data privacy statement of the respective network.

\- Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA; <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php>  
\- Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA; <https://twitter.com/privacy>  
\- Instagram LLC, 1601 Willow Rd, Menlo Park CA 94025, USA; <https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388>  
\- Google LLC,1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>[  
](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/)\- YouTube LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Brno, CA 94066, USA; [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=en)  
\- kununu GmbH, Neutorgasse 4-8, Top 3.02, 1010 Wien, AT; <https://privacy.xing.com/de/datenschutzerklaerung>  
\- whatchado GmbH, Möllwaldplatz 4/39, 1040 Wien, AT; <https://www.whatchado.com/de/terms>  
\- XING AG, Gänsemarkt 43, 20354 Hamburg, DE; <http://xing.com/privacy>  
\- LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; <http://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>

**5\. Your rights**

You have the right to demand information about the scope, origin and recipients of the data stored on you and the purpose of its storage at any time and without charge, Article 15 of the GDPR. Moreover, you can at any time demand that incorrect data be amended or deleted, Articles 16-17 of the GDPR. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the regulatory authority if you are of the opinion that your personal data is being processed in violation of the law, Article 77 of the GDPR.

 **6\. Your contact**
